Vasan Routh

Full Stack Game Developer | Mentor 🚣





🛂 vasanrouth@gmail.com 📞 8072290237

💡 Pondicherry, India 🛮 🔗 My Portfolio 💥

ABOUT ME

I love coding and playing games . I am a versatile Game Developer with over 5 years of experience, specializing in multiplayer games. And over 9 years of multidisciplinary programming experience. Published multiple games and had the opportunity to lead teams of awesome devs. Part-time Mentoring aspiring students to land jobs in the games industry:)

SKILLS

Engines

Unity (5+ Years), Unreal (1 + Years), Godot (1 + Years)

Languages

C, C++, C#, JavaScript (ES-ES2023), Java, Python, HTML, Solidity

Cloud/Networking

AWS, Azure, Google Cloud Platform, Firebase, Playfab, MongoDB, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Redis, Docker, ExpressJS, NodeJS, Socket.IO, Unity Networking (Photon, Mirror)

EDUCATION

Bachelor's Degree in Electronics & Communication Engg

·····

Pondicherry University

05/2017 - 06/2021 | Pondicherry, India

Highschool Diploma in Computer Science

Amalorpavam Hr. Sec. School 03/2015 - 03/2017 | Pondicherry, India

COURSES/CERTIFICATIONS

C and C++ Programming

An advanced course on OOPs and DSA

AWS Certified Developer Associate

Udemy course on using AWS tools and insights of each service.

EXPERIENCE

Game Dev Mentor

Outscal 🗷

06/2024 - Present | New Delhi, India

Unity, C++, C#, SFML, Design Patterns, Architecture

- Coaching students to learn game development, starting from OOPS to building a resume & portfolio,
- Helping them to clear interviews with ease and land jobs in top Game studios.

Indie Game Developer

Hitkraft Games ☑

02/2024 - Present | Chennai, India

Playfab, Cloudscript(JS), Google Cloud Run, AWS(Lambda), Photon, Unity, C#

- My own studio, working on a cool multiplayer word game, a mix of Boggle and Candy Crush [Check out] 2.
- Except Art and Audio, everything else is handled by me as a solo dev, from writing net code, local code, and game design too ^^

Lead Game Developer

Daceq.Ltd ☑

07/2022 - 01/2024 | London, UK

Unity, C#, ExpressJS, NodeJS, Photon Pun, Playfab, CloudRun, Moralis SDK, EtherJS, Solidity, Elasticsearch, Unity Cloud Build(CI/CD), Gamelift, Lambda, DynamoDB

- Lead a team of 5 to build an MMORTS game made with Unity (Hosting map servers, Buildings movement, Troop training, Combat mechanics, etc) [Check out] ☑
- My other work includes building a mix of Card + RTS genre-type mobile game for both Android and IOS platforms. [Check out] □

Game Developer

Creatr Studios Inc ☑

02/2020 - 06/2022 | Toronto, Canada

Unity, C#, GraphQL, ExpressJS, NodeJS, Photon, Playfab, CloudRun, Enjin SDK, Facebook SDK, Azure VM

- Interacted with Enjin cloud using GraphQL queries and mutations, performed safely in the Google Cloud Run (NodeJS) platform. [Check out] □
- Utilized Photon Cloud to transmit player inputs through RPC calls, keeping the game state in sync, with calls backed up in the cloud to cross-verify player actions.

Full-Stack Developer

IgniteSkylabs ☑

02/2018 - 02/2020 | Pondicherry, India

Unity, C#, Vuforia SDK, ARCore, ReactJS, NodeJS, Azure, MongoDB, Python, C#, Firebase, HTML

- Created web and mobile apps for startups and corporations like NCR, GE, HP,
- Developed an Indoor navigation AR mobile application in Unity 3D.
- Worked on other commercial projects, including an Automobile Tracking App and Education Apps